So then now
so this is what it is
that
you see wealth
when we want to sell
something that is destroying
somethin that is frugile, that is horrid
how do we do it. We have to make it look
most beautiful all will fire
and the holiest of holy.
hey walk like this you see.
Who are they?
They are the people of planning how
to rob the bank.
If you find like 3 people or 4 people
Seriously walking like this
you see, with an umbrella and complete
english dress. Becareful!
In a bank, must be somebody who is trying
to see how the bank is illuminated.
They plan it in such a beautiful manner,
the whole thing
the whole surface,
that it is very attractive.
They must make it attractive
They have to make it and there are so
many ways and methods
Actually somehow or the other they have
become through the
practice of this kind of cunning.
All their lies
,lies. So many lies, they have become
such experts that they can manage
and they do it
While you people
who are simple
are just lost
They say Mother, how can it be
Kundalini be that easy, that i think.
On the contrary if you avoid
you think it over
How can it be difficult?
Because it is a living proof.
It is a living happening for your
evolution.
What did you do to become a human being
from a monkey
and then what are you going to do
to become god from a human state
What exercise can you do about it?
It has to be a simple test.
like your own dreams
Like your own seeds, lik your own eyes
You've got your eyes.
why dont you marvel at the miracle
of your eyes. with which
you see is the complete canopy inside
such a miracle, that we take it for granted
that our eyes are with us, because ohh
very beautiful eyes
you take it for granted.
But just think of the miracle, these eyes,
from where have they come?
There is a wonderful book written,
Du Nuoy  has written known as Human Destiny
In which it says, that it is impossible
to believe
that law of chance has worked out
human beings
that through law of chance
we have evolved to be human beings
an impossibility because
with law of chance we could
be at the most, one amoeba
derived somewhere
But such a complicated
human mechanism that
has come on this earth
is impossible to us.
But all the kundalini knowledge
all the kundalini science
so far when i read it
I'm amazed.
I mean that is your mother.
And the mother that is the loving.
mother with the compassion of god
within you
which is waiting for these days to
get realisation.
But people are really funny, i must say
when i say that you did not do anything
about it, it works out
Usually they dont like it
They want to go through all
kinds of problems
and they want to do
all kinds of wrong things.
They want to be hit all the time today.
Why?
God never does like that.
It is doen in the simplest way.
In the easiest way.
In the most
comfortable way
So that you dont even feel the pinch
But according to kundalini Shashtra
so called as
these tantrikas
have horribly spoilt
you have to
burn yourself
and it must see the kundalini
rising
in
burning you
and there is heat in the body.
Actually
It is the cool breeze actually
It is written in the scriptures,
you get away with it from the holy spirit
we should get
wind of the holy spirit and Kundalini
if she is apart of that holy spirit
How can it give you feet?
When you try to do something
for which you are not obligued
then she punishes you
It is not you who punishes
But there is a deity who is sitting down
there at the first centre down below you
see in the next centre you see
there she
sits in the,in the pink centre she is there
and the red centre that is there
There is your deity!
and his the same deity
is regarded as incarnated on this earth
as our Lord Jesus Christ
This deity is the embodiment of innocence
That would give you a lashing
It tries to pursuade you, to dissuade you,
to tell you that dont go this way.
These people are horrid. They are trying
all kinds of nonsense
because they try to excite your sex
for your kundalini rising.
I mean this is something that is
beyond Me to understand
how, by doing sex have you become
human beings
from the monkey.
Can you connect it any way? Any way?
Thank God, we can see our brain is here,
our heart is here and sex is down there.
What is the connection?
in our awareness
if we have anything to do with sex?
Do you find a man who is very sexy
in anyway much more aware than others are?
I mean really, if you can,
or those who are supposed to be the people
who are raping
and doing all kinds of horrible things.
Do you find spiritually they are
divine people?
No, I mean I would like to know,
When tehy confuse Kundalini with sex,
is it in anyway, sublimating?
Then i ask about Christ,
because, atleast you know Christ,
I know you say,there may not be many modern
people but Christ,
who was a celibate personality
Sex has its own part
Marriage has its own part.
Everything is granted
but it has, and works,
but it has nothing to do with
your spiritual life
Thats the point.
If you have sanctified sex, it supports.
BUt how do you confuse these tow things
is really beyond my small brain
I cannot understand.
But, from the way the people are,
you must judge their spirituality.
I mean you have known, that people who have
been raping, are beastly people.
They rape and kill
They are not divine by any chance.
How do you connect
such advanced spiritual people, with God?
In which way do you find them divine?
Is a simple common sense
Apart from anything whatever is the
fact, youll find out yourself.
So the memory is much higher
In teh plain triangle, where this Ganesha
is sitting, down below
to protect, the chastity of his Mother.
So the sex and
kundalini has nothing to do
even saying it is being wrong.
Again it would be something like two
sex to the mind as far as being.
He miht be doing it.
He was, he hard horns in his head.
I dont understand the fellow
Whom you people have suddenly accepted
Just like that. For what?
HAs he had any one person
Any single mad man has
cured himself of madness,
apart from his dying of cancer.
He had a very unhappy life.
And if you read his own personal
life, it is terrible
I mean when you see their own life,
then atleast you must think are
we going to be with those lives ourselves?
You see when you try to follow somebody
You must see his own life.
You must find out what sort of a person
he is, what does he do?
How has he lived in this world?
How has he spent his life?
What has he achieved?
And then follow him.
Because somebody says something
must we follow him?
Afterall, if somebody says that,
I have achieved dome spiritual life
Alright, then lets see how he behaves.
That is positive
What does he do
We should see his own life
and we should see his own feat
How he acts.
If you put this test on all the gurus
put together all these fake and false
and horrid people, put together in five
cells, one worse than the other
They must have kids?
I mean in no scripture
It is described that the divine man
should have kids.
Is there?
There are all kids of
funny relationships with their desciples
Like a 80 year old Guru
will be carrying on with an 18 year old.
Just now today, i asked Jane
a very simple question.
I said that on the road we find,
not in India so common, but here
that the people are, young people
hugging each other, loving each other
but do they do it under these circumstances
supposing a  50 year old man
carrying on with a 15 year old girl
Do they do it on the road, she said, no
that they dont do it. Why?
Because you know with your common sense
that everybody is going to laugh at
your silliness and the stupidity
But these old Johnnies who have come here,
I dont understand, what there to follow?
And the ones who have written about
Kundalini also
have they told you anything about
themselves or have they given
anything good to anyone whatsoever?
I mean these are the common sense question
if you ask then you will know
how to know the reality.
Reality cannot convince,
because mentallyit cannot convince you,
but it can only make you understand
that this is not reality,
this is not reality. It is something else.
But when you face teh reality.
you start seeing it
and it is so tremendously different
But if i tell you, that sitting down here
I am feeling all your kundalinis. Is a fact
they are not in anyway
Not only, but all those who are realised
can feel your kundalini and can say
they feel your Kundalini and you will
also feel when you get your realisation
BUt this force, this dynamic force
is not acting only in this hall,
is acting all over.
It started
As yesterday the gentlemen said
Like crack.
it could go.
It goes and acts and works
and how it looks after you
that you have to see for yourself
because you are not in that, yet.
You have not yet
touched the shore of reality.
Thats why you think that
these governments and these
economics and these uh, what you call
political institutions and even
even spiritual institutions, have got it.
They are doing nothing,
Its all mockery going on.
The only one, who is the lord
and the king is God,
and the one who really
reigns over the whole world and universe
is He.
The one who has all the power
telecommunication and all kinds of
communications. It is He.
All are just you see like puppets
He is the one
who is using his string
as the prologue.
You must have seen in the prologue
in ancient times, even in India
They used to have a person
like a puppet you see.
He used to give the prologue
and he used to continue,
Uh Uh, tell
all about how the movements are going
going to be.
In teh same way it is the prologue
is done by somebody else
while the puppets are playing
and you think, it is the puppets
Who are the play.
But god is there
Yes, we believe in God
we have a picture of Christ.
Oh we do believe in god.
No doubt. And also you see
we believe in church, yes yes
we do believe in it.
Maha.. Why?
Have you found him?
Have you got him?
For you are
are now in the times
Time, time for you to get it.
You will get it.
So many of you have got it,
but you have to littlebit settle
down with it
Because as i told you
that there has been lots,
lots of damage in this country
by
people who brought you
ideas
saying this is reality.
They didnt introduce you to this reality.
Nothing happened within you,
but they gave you ideas
this is reality
Then somebody gives you ideas, like
When i was coming to England supposing
someboday says "Oh England
is great and in England this happens,
and in England that thing happens,"
and i come here, I find this is
happen and I feel so that
this is not reality.
Or if somebody says
England
somebody describes England like
say South Africa.
When I come here, I find Oh
so this is not.
Because these ideas, have come to you
from all these horrible
superficial, cunning, useless
materialistic people.
You have accepted the reality,
but reality is
very different and very beautiful
to be faced.
Each one of you should face it
and have it and enjoy it.
It is for all of you to get it.
Nobody can certify for you.
You have to certify yourself.
Now here,
We have some chakras as I told you
above of that
is the fontanel.
Second chakra which you see
is on top,
is the yellow one
in between the pink
triangular
bone
in the
spinal cord, at the end of spinal cord
is called, called the Kundalini.
you have reached the Kundalini.
Now why is it called the as serpent power?
its something
because any power
even electricity moves
and they thought
that this, because it moves like this,
Its better to call it as serpent power,
but it is not the power of a serpent.
You see when the adjective is
used before the noun
it does not mean
that the adjective becomes the noun
So once you say it is the power of a
of a serpent, everything goes wrong.
Now so that if it is like a power
of serpent and it bites you,
you must get, you see
all kinds of twitches and you can
get all kinds of dancing poses
and you can even take out your clothes
with you and everything can happen.
every sort of thing can happen to you
as soon as you change adjective
for the noun and noun for the adjective
Only in religion
they do like this, you see all
grammatically, but not anywhere else.
You will not find this mistake committed
anywhere else. They're very particular
but in this one when they said serpent
powers, that means it is like a serpent.
Or actually, at least minimum
it has something to do woth serpent
it is poisonous, it is horrid,
it is extremely heating up,
It will not heal you, it may finish.
You'll be surprised that Kundalini
can never harm.
You know we think that electricity
can be use for good purpose or bad purpose.
Atomic energy can be used for good purpose
or bad purpose, but not Sahaja Yoga.
Try.
You cannot.
If you want to kill someone through
Sahaja Yoga, you cannot.
You can cure people
but if you want somebody to hit you
You can
try it, all of the Sahaja Yogis
can try if they want to, they would not
but you cannot use because this is divine
pure power.
It would be something like saying that
nothing so pure in this world
but I can say if the water
see we can say, water washes people
and people can say
"No the water doesn't wash
but we can use the same water
for spoiling somebody's clothes"
It is water, or sort of
we can say that it can remove the pain.
That is not the quality of divine vibration
It is not.
Worldly things you can use for
both the purposes.
Thats why I said there is nothing so pure
and particulalry unique
as the divine vibration, really
which is never spoilt and is never,
never can be used for any bad purpose.
As soon as you start thinking about
about something bad, vibration
will stop immediately.
As soon as you think of harming someone
your vibrations will stop.
As soon as your mind goes onto
some sort of a destructive
plan, vibrations stop forcefully.
you get something else.
And so many things happen that you cannot
do it and if you try to do it
you lose your vibrations
It's a very sensitive.
So you cannot use it for any bad purpose.
That is absolutley sure answer.
Now see how beautifully you are made
Il show you the red one, then the yellow
then the green, then you have got the blue
Then the one that looks like a small
the here is the white, the pistol
and then on top.
These seven chakras are there
And all these seven chakras, one by one
If you see in the charts, you have got
the full idea about the seven chakras
the deities that are sitting on them
and how they help.
And what is the sympathetic term
what is the parasympathetic, what is the
left side, what is the right side
of the man and what is the lower side.
The lower side of the man is hell.
The left side of the man is the subconcious
The right side of man is the supraconcious
by which we plan for the future
We are ambitious about it and here is
Take it easy
We work it out and it works
and you can get it.
We have had people who where difficult
but they have got it.
So many people have got it,
so you should also get it
and all over the worl people are getting so
so there's no harm in taking.
But if you want to make it sort of cheap
stuff, you can
Its not cheap.
Its the most precious.
Its the most vineer
and theres a great protocol for it.
People are to such an extent, sometimes
They take liberties with it
They will use it for small things like
O should I go today to this place or not?
Should i see the vibrations. if you start
using it for cheap things, it goes away
That awareness wont be there.
For example, this machine
can be used by me, can be used any thug
can be used by anything
it doesnt have any meaning.
But vibrations do.
When you are connected with your spirit,
they discriminate and they find out.
If you try to play tricks with it,
in the beginning all the Sahaja Yogis try
in the beginning, but then they give up
understanding that it doesnt have.
When the vibrations are flowing in you
you feel completely peaceful
Absolutely.
It is a blissful state
You are enjoy and you start enjoying life.
Actually, your life begins that time.
Ive seen people who where completely
bored with life. They didnt know what to do
They were bored of themselves.
Like you see punk rock people,
if you go and talk to them
they say "We were bored, who to do"
so they are doing punk rock.
Like that peopl are, who are bored
start doing all kinds of things
but after Sahaja Yoga, your life
becomes so charming
Every moment you enjoy everything.
If it is absurd, you enjoy it as a joke.
If it is funny, you enjoy it as funny thing
If it is cruel, you will put your attention
on it and see to it,that it is done alright
So you see you sort of become part and
parcel of that universal being
and you start feeling that
you have an identification
You have a meaning.
You are fixed up in an instrument
which is living and which is working
and you are part of that instrument
and you feel the rapport.
But by thinking you cannot do.
That is one thing you must know.
By thinking you cannot know the reality,
because thinking is a limited process
of a limited mind.
It is a triggering.
When it happens, a triggering
Then suddenly what happens,
the whole thing flows
and you become one with that divine
You cannot do it by rationalizing it.
"Oh I can work it out
I can put my thoughts alright"
Thats not the way.
You cannot work it out.
Its a living process
that works out like the sprouting of a seed
it works out, and it comes down
and it just happens to you, by itself.
You cannot think about it.
The more you start thinking about it,
the further it goes away.
You cannot think about it,
It just happens and you become.
You become that.
So first what happens is you become
thoughtlessly aware.
When the kundalini rises
upon that centre of Agnya
this is the centre of Christ.
It is placed between the pituitary
and pineal in the centre
which you can see in your all chart.
When it crosses that
you become absolutely free
there is no thought.
But when kundalini pierces this portion
you start getting a cool breeze in the hand
A wave.
You start getting the cool breeze
in your hand.
If the cool breeze hasnt started,
or you are getting a tingly
must be something wrong,
physically, mentally, emotionally with you
which can be corrected.
So the Kundalini itself corrects
but for the first time most of the people
feel it, you see it is Kundalini is
is a wonderful thing, because she says
first let me give you an experience
so that it remembers.
You must remember the experience
so it gives you a shock.
You feel. But then what happens
it comes down and cures you
here, there, there. Again it goes.
Then again it comes down
It starts curing you
part by part and part by part.
Ultimately if you actively cure and have
it, and feel  the vibrations all the time
there, completely established
So one shlould not get upset about it
You see though Sahaja Yoga is the quickest
and the only way, but still
we have to get your instrument corrected
this is the problem.
And unless and until the instrument
is corrected, nothing can work.
So this is what it is
and if you have to get the realisation
you have to know one thing
that the people who are very superficial
nature, cannot get it
You have to be deeply seeking otherwise
it doesnt work. It doesnt work on you.
And here, we are not like other people
who say come along, come along, come along
we must come. No!
If you come with your will.
If you come in your freedom.
If you are really seeking,then its alright.
The other day we had one gentleman
a very fat gentleman had come
and he was saying to me
that one man had a risen Kundalini
and his got spoiled and some
damage has been done, so i said alright
You'll have to do Sahaja Yoga. Your
kundalini has not risen
nothing of the kind.
Somebody has told you lies, you have to
believe in it. He said
I dont believe in this,
I dont want to do this
I said, Why are you wasting my time?
You better go.
Why do you have waste my time?
Why do you want to trouble?
Because if you do not believe in all this
you should better go,
Because, you are not paying anything
I am spending my time for you
And if you donot want to have it
better go
He was quite amazed at me.
You want me to go away?
Ofcourse, yes
When you will feel that
you can, but not like this.
If you donot cooperate?
Why should god cooperate?
Think of it
So this is not a public thing,
stance goin on
or any kind of a speaking for election
Even if you have one person, its alright
But we do not want people
here, just have some, you see
to know that we have been guru shopping.
we have not seen this shopping, this shop.
We dont want that.
This is definetely a thing
where it doesn't sell.
It is you who are teh seekers.
It is you who are out to and
have to get it in your own right.
That is your right.
BUt if you want to deny your right,
Im not going to call at you,
please, please, please take it.
Ofcourse, im not so harsh like others are.
You see, they could be very harsh,
even Christ you see.
Could be harsh to say, Get Out
I dont want to see your face
You are a small believer.
You see it really sometimes surprises
the way people go on ordering
the incarnations, you see that
you must do this, you must cure my father
you must cure my grandfather
you must cure my mother.
you must cure my great great great
grandfather, then only il come to you
Sort of a shopping goes on,
see, sort of bargaining.
There is no bargaining with god.
It is not possible.
Just have it, because it is your right.
In your own prestige
in your own dignity you have it,
in all your freedom you have it.
And you should enjoy it.
But there cannot be any bargaining about it
If you try to bargain it will run way
it will recede immediately.
There are some people now, some very big
supposed to be very big people
The're comign to see, just to talk
about it. I said "Im not going to talk
to you. Im not interested. Are they coming
for seeking only?" she said
"Yeah, they were seeking."
I said "they come, let them come as seekers
but if they are coming to tell me a
big lecture and give me a big lecture
Im not listerning."
You see because i know that kind.
Ive seen many of them and im not
going to waste any more energy
for the lecture giving people.
They can go to the hyde park
and stand on the soap box.
Like lecturer standing
You see this happened with many people,
You see they just come to torture you
for nothing at all. I mean sort off
they try to show off. They are not sick
and that is why you have to shut it there
alright finished, because this
is not a shop.
If you can reverse.
If you could understand, no, we are seekers
we have to be.
Its a blessing of god almighty.
There are all these beautiful flowers
of God.
Where i go same.
I'll work very hard.
I'll never.
Because sometimes, some of the
Sahaja Yogis are lost, I really go out
of the way to save them
But who is going to run after Hitler
to save him?
If you expect that, it is wrong.
It is wrong. You have not understood
You have not understood the dignity
of divine.
The most dignified thing
is the Kingliness of the divine,
and its not going to fall at your feet
for your realisation.
If human beings say for example
do not accept realisation and they want
to accept and destroy it.
It can be created again
the whole world can be created by God.
What does it matter to him.
He can create thousands and thousands
of people.
BUt it is for human beings to realise
that the time has come
for our forefather has created
this beautiful earth and created
all this for us, and it is for us
to grasp in it, and to get in it. And
whatever he wants to do, let us have it.
There is another side to God, ofcourse.
Its not all the time, which we try
to sort of.
As a mother I admit
to the people, please have this. I will try
The other side of it, is a different style.
So in all dignity, in all understanding
in all majesty,
you receive it.
Receive it, and enjoy the citizenship
of Gods grace and enjoy all the power
of your own being.
These are your own
they are inside,
and i only give you the key.
I will give you teh key to open it.
And once you have it, you have the key
and these are all your wealth to yourself
and to the whole world.
Because this world is such, which you
cannot enjoy without others.
You have to enjoy in the company of others.
You cannot enjoy alone.
It is so plain.
You wont find some people to whom
you want to tell this, " Oh this has
happened, Isn't it true or not
It happens to you.
BUt he shudders to see, in telling people
"Oh you are a yoga, should i tell him
or not, because he punched me."
If i tell him that I pound him.
You have to see.
By gods grace we have lots of people
now in London and also we are developing
now contacts outside, and so we are going
to have many more and then you can share
your problems, and also your enjoyment and
that is what we are here for
Now in such a short time
I cannot tell you all about the chakras,
but this is all written down, thank God
so you can read it, its quite boring
Otherwise
You better have your realisation now.
Best thing is to have your realisation.
Now, those who have been sitting like this
Are you all wearing your shoes?
Please take the out. Shoes are
little bit you see, that why I came down
from there because I thought the vibrations
would be better, that why I came down.
So its better to take out the shoes
so that you can, you see, feel it more.
Just take out your shoes and put your
hands down.
Why dont you take off your shoes.
Now im telling you
Take off your shoes.
Just take out your shoes.
Keep your hands there.
Those who have come for the first time
should come forward.
good idea, those who have come for first
time, please do come
come, you can come
Just over here. Just come.
Little forward, so that it be
Good, Not to be afraid
and lost.